<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-02T11:21:49+01:00</updated><id>http://5loaves2fish.blog//</id><title type="html">5loaves2fish</title><subtitle>When you want more</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Franciscan wedding plan, yes we can!</title><link href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Franciscan wedding plan, yes we can!" /><published>2016-12-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://5loaves2fish.blog/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://5loaves2fish.blog/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can/">&lt;p&gt;I heard this sentence a thousand times: “We can’t get married because we’ve got no money”, where by &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s meant that for the reception. So: first there is the dress, the restaurant, the flowers, the car, the historic church, the photographer, the entertainment, the honeymoon, etc. Then we should please her mum who couldn’t afford much in her days and now wants her daughter’s wedding to be the best one. And don’t forget her family is very large and they are a close family. So, just considering the most intimate ones, they are 150. And what about the little cousins, uncles, aunties, relatives here and relatives there, until the fifth generation on the mom’s side? Well it’s not nice not inviting them, they have been important for me… I absolutely have to find the aunt’s phone number… what was her name??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short: &lt;strong&gt;planning a wedding is a huge stress and, if you think of it this way, it is only affordable to a few Sheikh oil kings.&lt;/strong&gt; But then, let me say, those poor souls that will have to come to this wedding and sit at the tables —which have already been planned by the groom on a night when he was finally free because he fought with his future bride for the color of the wedding announcement— how much will they have to spend for you? In fact at a wedding like this you need to be well dressed, and you can’t wear the dress that you recycled from your sister’s wedding: people can see it in the pictures and it’s embarrassing! And don’t forget the present! Oh gosh, the present! How much are these guys spending for us? At least 60$ per person for a piece of raw lasagna and a dessert that gives stomachache… damn, this means you’re forced to give 100$ each (at least!). Well, there are five of us, what can we do? I can foresee the vacation at the beach house skipping for a wedding, noooo!!! I know it: Chiara will certainly have a fever (even if it’s June), yes: a sudden illness because her grandparents took her to the mountains where there was a bad weather. We can’t give up the beach house for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start over!&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s start all over from the beginning. So, first of all, why are we getting married? Who has to absolutely be there that day? Who are we organizing this party for? &lt;strong&gt;Marriage is primarily a vocation&lt;/strong&gt;, a call to love and joy. It will surely be the best day of our lives, even without a mortgage to set it up (it will be the best day for the &lt;em&gt;promise&lt;/em&gt; it brings, not for the &lt;em&gt;emotions&lt;/em&gt; of the moment). It may have a better start with the rent paid for three months, instead of 15 minutes of fireworks. The main host, if we can call it so, will be the Lord. If He won’t be there everything will simply gets harder and harder. Then, let’s retrace the passages of the Gospel that have marked our history. A week before the big yes, let’s go on a nice retreat, just the two of us, in some hermitage to pray, to fully enter into the mystery of the sacrament we are about to receive. Perhaps during the celebration we can tell the story of providence and beauty that we experienced, so that everyone can be grateful to the Lord and help us to thank Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the organization? The lunch, the music, the dances … the party is for guests, but for sure we are the celebrated ones; so we ourselves need to have fun first. Following the standards perhaps doesn’t always reflect our personalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get into practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-organize-a-beautiful-wedding&quot;&gt;How to organize a beautiful wedding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The announcement:&lt;/strong&gt; we took an A4 sheet and we used the printer at home, which works fine. We divided it into four parts. On the first side there was the invitation to the ceremony and the reception with a clear indication for the gift: “The Lord loves the cheerful giver. As a gift we would like a lot of money. Give what you can —and then Fr. Giovanni Marini forced us to add —and &lt;strong&gt;more than you can&lt;/strong&gt;. This money will be donated to an orphanage in Mozambique”. Below that there was a small map that showed how to reach the church and the reception place, and on the back we gave details about the mission in Mozambique. Alternatively, one can even use the invitations themselves to support those in need. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativelab.5p2p.it/&quot;&gt;we support the projects of Sant’Antonio church in Milan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dress:&lt;/strong&gt; on the Internet you can find really cheap stuff. I was lucky to have a mother who took on the role of dressmaker on the occasion, and so I just spent about 300$ for the fabric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flowers:&lt;/strong&gt; never say they are for a wedding, they’ll fleece you! Five days before the wedding, I went with my sister’s friend to buy 150 gerberas —my favorite flower— and she told the florist they were for a super-Franciscan wedding, meaning that he could not ask for more than 150$, and indeed it was so. At the wedding of a friend of mine, I’ve decorated the church myself: two or three compositions here and there, and a flower on each bench, tied with a ribbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photographer:&lt;/strong&gt; if you rely on a professional, in most cases you will end up with someone who ignores the deep meaning of that day. Lacking the necessary sensitivity, he will pretend to direct the day without really understanding your needs. Here are two solutions: the first is to give the role to a friend who has passion for photography and the necessary equipment. The second option is to call &lt;a href=&quot;http://weddings.5p2p.it&quot;&gt;5loaves2fish&lt;/a&gt; (yes! we also do that). In fact, the posts you are reading, the videos and our witnessing are completely funded by our wedding photography activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; location??? What? 5,000$? What? A parish hall is always easy to find, perhaps with a nice garden (which you’ll really enjoy, if it doesn’t rain —as it happened at our wedding— or you can do it at the country house of a cousin who lives out of town (in France they have this habit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch:&lt;/strong&gt; if the parish hall has a kitchen, you just have to add some scout friend who knows how to get by in any situation, or some volunteer who doesn’t want to give up the beach house to make you a gift; otherwise caterer, nice paper plates, plastic steam glasses and a bit of creativity. My father, for example, brought wine, my grandmother cheese, we bought some cold cuts from a farm, a friend made the cake, the caterer prepared a lasagna and the second course with a side (900€, waiters included, for 80 people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The entertainer:&lt;/strong&gt; a friend who plays the piano bar, a good stereo, etc. Tarantella dance never goes out of fashion…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wedding-mobile:&lt;/strong&gt; as for the car, your cheap car works fine; polished as it was new, with hitched cans hung on the back, it looks cool ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, for our wedding we spent about 2,000$, including the offer for the church and the 10 nights we spent in the adjoining guesthouse. &lt;strong&gt;The most important thing is to put the most important things first&lt;/strong&gt;, and everything else around them. The most important thing is not to be sucked into this chasm of organization, and then look up. At our wedding many guests were in jeans, but we really enjoyed ourselves. The most beautiful gifts were the envelopes full of small change from my college friends, who really gave up a pizza for it and they did it from the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes you can, what do you say?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alescanca</name></author><summary type="html">I heard this sentence a thousand times: “We can’t get married because we’ve got no money”, where by money, it’s meant that for the reception. So: first there is the dress, the restaurant, the flowers, the car, the historic church, the photographer, the entertainment, the honeymoon, etc. Then we should please her mum who couldn’t afford much in her days and now wants her daughter’s wedding to be the best one. And don’t forget her family is very large and they are a close family. So, just considering the most intimate ones, they are 150. And what about the little cousins, uncles, aunties, relatives here and relatives there, until the fifth generation on the mom’s side? Well it’s not nice not inviting them, they have been important for me… I absolutely have to find the aunt’s phone number… what was her name??</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://5loaves2fish.blog/images/posts/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Is he the one?</title><link href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/is-he-the-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is he the one?" /><published>2016-12-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://5loaves2fish.blog/is-he-the-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://5loaves2fish.blog/is-he-the-one/">&lt;p&gt;And finally, where do I find such a superman willing to pursue me, pursue me? I still have adolescent acne, a butt which is larger than Texas and I have not yet learned how to upload pictures on the computer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some answers for the first two questions, such as these: the perfect man does not exist in reality; or… perhaps I know one, but my friend took him while I was looking for a splinter in his eye. And again, maybe there is, and surely I’ll find him and he will fall at my feet, but no one believes it; actually neither do I. The answer to the third question was clear and firm: “No one would ever choose me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just some thoughts; thoughts of teen Alessandra in her room as she looks at her new pimple in the mirror and says “hell!” In high school I was the friend of the &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; one. So I was the &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; one. &lt;strong&gt;That is, while I was thinking about the coolest guy ever of my life, no one cared about me.&lt;/strong&gt; If someone was flirting with me, he was just embarrassing. Actually I wasn’t much concerned about it because I really felt beautiful inside and my inner life was growing more and more in my deep relationship with God. This used to take a lot of space in my day, both in parish activities and in moments of solitude spent reading the psalms, often surrounded by nature under a big tree on top of a hill. The more space I gave to these things the more I felt fulfilled; so much so that I thought that all I wanted from life was to devote myself to God and to others. Yes, becoming a nun, that was the thing that gave me immense joy. So, after the example of St. Francis and with the enthusiasm of the friars and nuns that I spent time with in Assisi, I put on a pair of sandals, despite the cold of winter and the laughs of my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Father Giovanni, a friar who was my spiritual director, understood where I wanted to end up. And without even talking explicitly about it, he started saying stuff like “&lt;strong&gt;you must learn how to court a man first and then we can try to court God!&lt;/strong&gt;   So you have to court at least 10 guys and then choose the best. No fussing, look among the guys you already know. Go! Don’t forget that the man thinks with the eye: short skirt (very short indeed) heels, makeup, styled hair, etc. Hurry up!”. In fact I hadn’t had any important love story at that time (I was only 17!) So what he said made sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now &lt;strong&gt;where do I find a guy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I find him, he will never want me! I went to the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Porziuncola Church&lt;/a&gt; and thought about whom of the friends in my life I looked up to and who could be worth having a story with. Immediately I thought of my friend Francesco, whom I had met the year before at the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Franciscan March&lt;/a&gt;, but with him it would have never worked. First of all, he belonged to the superman category. Also, he worked in Switzerland and was eight years older than me. Anyway, I took him as a benchmark; he represented the top. Then I made a deal with the Lord: “I am willing to court a man and put on skirts, heels, makeup and everything else only if he is a man (not a kid), that is more or less like my friend Francesco, from him up, I will not settle for less even to go drink a coffee.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, though, a couple of months after that morning at the Porziuncola, Francesco began to call me and to pay attention to me. &lt;a href=&quot;/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life&quot;&gt;He too, was going on his own path&lt;/a&gt;. I began to engage in this relationship, in obedience to Father Giovanni’s suggestions. At first it was just to prove to myself that my life was somewhere else. What scared me most in having a relationship with a guy was that he could take me away from my deep relationship with God. I did not think something so intimate could be shared with anyone else. I fell in love with him head over feet. Not only I was wrong, but that intimacy deeply increased. It was all the more beautiful, more mature, more concrete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion: I met the right man at the Franciscan March, I recognized him as a man I respected in the Porziuncola, and I realized that he was the right one &lt;strong&gt;because he wasn’t perfect, but he could get in the game&lt;/strong&gt;. He made me breathe air of freedom when we were talking about the choices I had to do at the university, and, very importantly, he &lt;a href=&quot;/indeed-he-was-right&quot;&gt;knew how to argue and start again&lt;/a&gt; (which has been very useful) every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; onclick=&quot;location.href='/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life';&quot;&gt;Follow up&lt;/button&gt; on this story by reading Francesco’s version!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alescanca</name></author><summary type="html">And finally, where do I find such a superman willing to pursue me, pursue me? I still have adolescent acne, a butt which is larger than Texas and I have not yet learned how to upload pictures on the computer…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://5loaves2fish.blog/images/posts/is-he-the-one.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Is she the woman of my life?</title><link href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is she the woman of my life?" /><published>2016-11-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://5loaves2fish.blog/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://5loaves2fish.blog/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life/">&lt;p&gt;Sure of finding my way in life, I started a journey of faith under the guidance of a friar I had met in Assisi shortly before. At that time I had already been through some serious love stories. However, although I enjoyed dating those girls, I never really considered starting a family or marrying any of them… I didn’t find any interest in such plan, because, let’s face it, family life is like a prison! A burdensome life where everything revolves around three things: work, children, and home, the whole package garnished with a car, vacations, and an annoying wife. No adventures, no challenges, no chance to engage with others. Not a fascinating perspective indeed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing my standpoint, Fr. Max invited me to go to meet a so-called christian &lt;strong&gt;family&lt;/strong&gt;. After a series of unsuccessful gentle attempts using good manners, the friar eventually convinced me with a kick in the butt! I was thinking: who are these people? I don’t even know them! And most importantly, what the hell do they know about me and my life? Despite these thoughts, I had nothing to lose and so I reluctantly decided to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed in Fiumicino (Rome) and drove for more than 4 hours to get to Manfredonia, Gargano, Puglia (south of Italy). Eventually, I arrived at &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Mimmo &amp;amp; Cinzia&lt;/a&gt; Armiento’s place. It was August. The first morning we went to the beach, in the evening we ate pizza and on August 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt;, the day of forgiveness, we sang prayers. Among all, what I will never forget is a brief conversation I had with Mimmo. Sheltered from the heat under a tree, for the first time in my life I started imagining my future wife. Mimmo was asking me some questions, and he immediately got to the point. He asked me which relationships mattered the most in my life. I had no doubts. My friends from Rome I used to go rock climbing with: Piero, Claudio… why? I explained him: “… when you climb a mountain, you entrust your life to your rope partner. He is the one who holds the rope, he is the one will hold you if you fall. Our lives are held together by this mutual absolute blind trust”. In this view of relationships there was adventure, there was the courage of giving yourself up for the other 100%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mimmo look at me and said “You know, my wife Cinzia is exactly this to me: &lt;strong&gt;she is my rope partner for life&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard these words, I was puzzled. I had never heard something like that. Especially about someone’s wife, who by definition is a pain in the a**, hysterical, obsessive, generally incompetent, psychologically unstable, always dissatisfied and overweight. In Italy there is even a song about it, which goes something like “Why? Why on Sundays do you always leave me alone? […] but one day I’ll come with you”; the perfect picture of an annoying woman; her husband’s response must have been “because at least on Sundays I can catch a breath! Even prisoners have yard time, don’t they?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my experiences, Mimmo’s words sounded like an epiphany. I had never thought or imagined that a wife could be a rope partner and a reliable good life companion. He invited me to think about what characteristics a hypothetical woman should have for her &lt;strong&gt;to be a good rope partner for my life&lt;/strong&gt;. And, as I was listing these qualities in my mind, I realized that the women I had dated so far did not embody pretty much any of them. This gave me confidence. So it is true, not all women are like that! There is a chance for me too to meet &lt;strong&gt;my rope partner!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been searching for the wrong person in the wrong places; but now I had a map. I started thinking of all my friends and acquaintances to see if, by any chance, one of them matched these new parameters. After pondering for a while, my search delivered one —one only— result… it was her. It is her. And I stayed up all night unable to sleep…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I called her and, shyly, we began our climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; onclick=&quot;location.href='/is-he-the-one';&quot;&gt;Follow up&lt;/button&gt; to read how it has been for my wife!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Francesco</name></author><summary type="html">Sure of finding my way in life, I started a journey of faith under the guidance of a friar I had met in Assisi shortly before. At that time I had already been through some serious love stories. However, although I enjoyed dating those girls, I never really considered starting a family or marrying any of them… I didn’t find any interest in such plan, because, let’s face it, family life is like a prison! A burdensome life where everything revolves around three things: work, children, and home, the whole package garnished with a car, vacations, and an annoying wife. No adventures, no challenges, no chance to engage with others. Not a fascinating perspective indeed!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://5loaves2fish.blog/images/posts/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What was the hurry?</title><link href="http://5loaves2fish.blog/what-was-the-hurry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What was the hurry?" /><published>2016-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://5loaves2fish.blog/what-was-the-hurry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://5loaves2fish.blog/what-was-the-hurry/">&lt;p&gt;We were sitting at the table when my dad, struck at the sight of that ring, began a true father-to-daughter talk. Trying to figure out what that ring meant, he started by saying how important family is, how the values​​ he and my mom passed down to me are the foundation for life, and how commendable it was that Francesco and I were taking things seriously, BUT… :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alessandra you have to understand that the family is the most important thing. Family comes first, BUT you cannot improvise it: first you have to graduate, then you have to find a good job —maybe stable—, then don’t forget to save money in order to buy a nice house; and then you can get married.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excuse me dad, but didn’t the family come first?! It seems it comes last, when you’ve done everything else. They don’t require you have a degree in order to get married, at most you need to have received Confirmation!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… (Here I would put a picture of my dad stricken as if it was by lightning).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, necessary to soften the blow, my dad, moved, looked into the eyes of my mum and said: “We lost her”, meaning that he understood that in a short time I would have left home forever, that is I would have married soon. But actually the truth was different. The truth was that Francesco and I had already decided to get married. We had already set the date and booked the church. We had already made a promise of faithfulness to one another, followed by a brief blessing by Fr. Massimo. It happened one evening after praying the Vespers, at the altar of the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Porziuncola&lt;/a&gt; after everyone else had left the church, with a bouquet of scented red roses and only a few lit candles. We hugged and dreamt about all the things we wanted to do together as a married couple. We didn’t want to tell anyone because it seemed too precious, and, most of all, we knew it would have caused reactions and scandals. I am saying scandal because I was getting married at 19 years old (I would have become 20 a month after the wedding!), without a degree, without a steady job (especially if the only job involved is a researcher at the university!), without a house, and above all… without being pregnant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the hurry? Why at 20 years old? Why not wait until everything is perfect? Why be so hasty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rush is the same that John and Peter had running together to the tomb to see Jesus resurrected (Jh20,4): the haste of explosive joy, of the love that can’t wait, impatient love, the love that asks you all of yourself. Love doesn’t ask you if you plan to graduate on time, or if you have economic stability. I don’t think that a marriage with a permanent job (if only it was easy to find!) is a better marriage.  Likewise, I don’t think that a marriage between two graduates has more value. But &lt;strong&gt;I definitely think that it takes three to get married successfully&lt;/strong&gt;, because in addition to the spouses there is a third: the Lord. Yes, I think a marriage with God is definitely better and more fun because you are not alone: you have someone who in the difficult times wants to get His hands dirty with you, who supports you when you make a mess, and who is your Father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always asked God to give me the grace to spend my youth for my vocation. What I felt as urgent was not to waste time with anything that was a frill, but rather to &lt;strong&gt;hit the target as soon as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. For me the target is God and my vocation is the way to serve Him, the place where I can spend myself, where I can meet Him. Why put something before joy, why wait?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love calls. Love is urgent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nearly eight years of marriage we don’t have a house, we don’t have a permanent job, and I did not graduate (my last exams are in July!). But we have more and more certainties: the chaos, always including, a huge pile of laundry to hang out, the presence of my husband next to me, our daily yes in joy and quarrels, our beautiful children with their chronic wildness, and providence. We lived in four different countries, with four different languages, we moved a thousand times, but we haven’t forgotten our goal, and that hurry hasn’t left us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alessandra</name></author><summary type="html">We were sitting at the table when my dad, struck at the sight of that ring, began a true father-to-daughter talk. Trying to figure out what that ring meant, he started by saying how important family is, how the values​​ he and my mom passed down to me are the foundation for life, and how commendable it was that Francesco and I were taking things seriously, BUT… :</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://5loaves2fish.blog/images/posts/what-was-the-hurry.jpg" /></entry></feed>
