<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-26T15:12:15+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">5loaves2fish</title><subtitle>When you want more</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Women, masters of idealization - You are not who you used to be</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-are-not-who-you-used-to-be" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Women, masters of idealization - You are not who you used to be" /><published>2017-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/women-masters-of-idealization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-are-not-who-you-used-to-be">&lt;p&gt;One thing I’m very proud of is to be able to understand and speak different languages, even if I haven’t succeeded in understanding the male language yet (but I’m sure I’ll make it sooner or later!). We have been living around Europe for already six years: first in Switzerland, then in France and now in Germany. A few days ago, while I was walking in Paris, I overheard a conversation between two lovers in a rocky relationship.. Every third word, she was repeating this sentence: “ Tu n’est pas plus comme avant!”, “Tu n’étais pas comme ça avant!” (…You are not who you used to be, you weren’t like this before). Hearing her words I realized two things: first, we women are all alike, from Paris to Palermo, from New York to Freiburg; second, I think I could start writing an encyclopedia universally accepted to be titled “The female universe, to make no mistake always play the shopping card”, of at least a million pages only in the first volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Italian women are more demanding, French are more formal and German are more strapping (they manage to put a beer crate in the car with one hand while holding the baby with the other one), all the women I know are very good idealizers. How much we love to project on the other what we would like to HAVE! We want. We want perfection. If some poor man who approaches us is barely polite, we go home picturing him while preparing a delicious dinner for us with lots of candles and willing to change diapers, while we lie in the garden sniffing the bouquet of thirty red roses he has just given us. We are serious in this stuff: we are all professional movie directors. Not to mention if this poor guy lives by himself. What a charm! He indeed knows how to get by! He will never expect me to do things at home because he is used to do them; he deals with everything very well and understands that the issue concerns both of us (warning girls! My husband used to live by himself too, but he is allergic to housework). In short, we women all speak the same language: we always idealize the man in front of us, always demanding more from those unfortunates who approach us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An obvious question arises: couldn’t it be that he has always been like that, while we have disguised him as a perfect man, without ever seeing him for whom he was? In the early days of a relationship we all think that we are dealing with an angel came down from Heaven, who will meet all of our expectations. Then, when the falling-in-love period ends (which is after at most a couple of years), one has to face the fact that he is a sinner, who, after all, is just like you. Suddenly defects appear, expectations are disappointed, and you realize he even has ugly hair on his right ear and loves to wear socks with sandals — the most anti-sexy thing you can see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine always says that disappointment is always the result of an &lt;strong&gt;illusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the time of Love as a choice, because true Love is a choice, not just butterflies in the stomach. Love can start from an attraction, a strong esteem or some complicity, but above all it is a choice. Look around. Think of a mother (ME) who gets up at 3 am to feed the baby and change diapers. Do you think that Love has anything to do with butterflies? The answer is NO, I would like to sleep and not be bothered at least at night. Or, does a wife who prepares dinner for her husband after a bad day spent with three brats have any butterflies in her stomach? The answer is still NO. Do you think it was out of a romantic feeling that Christ died on the cross for you?
But then…is Love a duty without feelings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t choose this man because he fits my requirements, and not even because he will make me happy. I choose him because &lt;strong&gt;I want to make him happy&lt;/strong&gt;, I Love him and I think it’s worth spending my life with him (… even though we should talk again about the socks with sandals). St Francis is right: it is by giving that we receive. It is by spending your life for someone that you feel fulfilled. The butterflies in the stomach are a stage, beautiful and important, but if love fails to become a choice, if you don’t get your hands dirty, it is shallow and usually ends up with a nice blow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband isn’t who he used to be, he is much &lt;strong&gt;better&lt;/strong&gt; to my eyes since I decided to see him for whom he is. To see him and not my illusions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alessandra</name></author><summary type="html">One thing I’m very proud of is to be able to understand and speak different languages, even if I haven’t succeeded in understanding the male language yet (but I’m sure I’ll make it sooner or later!). We have been living around Europe for already six years: first in Switzerland, then in France and now in Germany. A few days ago, while I was walking in Paris, I overheard a conversation between two lovers in a rocky relationship.. Every third word, she was repeating this sentence: “ Tu n’est pas plus comme avant!”, “Tu n’étais pas comme ça avant!” (…You are not who you used to be, you weren’t like this before). Hearing her words I realized two things: first, we women are all alike, from Paris to Palermo, from New York to Freiburg; second, I think I could start writing an encyclopedia universally accepted to be titled “The female universe, to make no mistake always play the shopping card”, of at least a million pages only in the first volume.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/women-masters-of-idealization.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">With eyes closed - faith beyond what you see</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/with-eyes-closed-faith-beyond-what-you-see/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With eyes closed - faith beyond what you see" /><published>2017-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/with-eyes-closed-faith-beyond-what-you-see</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/with-eyes-closed-faith-beyond-what-you-see/">&lt;p&gt;You have listened to a beautiful announcement in &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Assisi&lt;/a&gt;. You have been struck and moved by the depth of those words that went straight into the heart. You have seen a truth in them, a truth about your life. You have realized there’s no use in living for those few things you used to fight for, which gave you nothing but burdens in exchange for false certainties. Maybe you were distant and thanks to the announcement in Assisi you have converted and you’ve approached the Church, that mother that everyone judges. You have encountered the Lord. &lt;em&gt;You have believed in a great beauty&lt;/em&gt;, in a promise of happiness no one ever made to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the day comes when things &lt;strong&gt;don’t go the way you expected&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One disappointment after the other, you wonder where the hell is the fulfillment of those promises. A choked cry inside your heart. Everything collapses. Faith collapses, hope collapses; there is no truth. I have been cheated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Francesco and I are part of a long stream of people who went to &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Assisi&lt;/a&gt;. There we heard strong announcements, which disrupted our plans and encouraged us to change our lives, &lt;em&gt;to discover an essential beauty&lt;/em&gt;. At that point we couldn’t help but leave everything and immediately seize all those good things we heard of. It was like that for us. After a spiritual journey in Assisi we got married with no certainties. We were 20 years old, we hadn’t finished college, we didn’t have a permanent job nor much consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things didn’t really go the way we had imagined. After just one year in Rome we were forced to move to France with our three-month baby. We didn’t know anyone there, we couldn’t speak a word of French and we felt really alone. It was a tough period. After some time I found myself with two little girls, with a workaholic husband who was never home, in a culture where children are considered mere brats, where mothers hang out only when their children are not around, where pre-school is an essential and supreme goal (even for those who don’t work and have nothing to do!), with pending university studies and especially with a relation on the edge of failure…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God where are you? What are you doing to us? Us, who left everything to answer your call to marriage! Lord, we understood that everything was gonna be great, challenging and tiring but beautiful, blessed by You. What’s going on???&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times when you feel you have been utterly cheated on, and you send to hell friars, nuns, friends who are ahead of you on the path of life and who told you beautiful things. When you find yourself married, standing in front of your husband, and things just haven’t worked out for months, when you don’t understand each other anymore, you become speachless. &lt;em&gt;After this long journey together, what is left?&lt;/em&gt; A desolate marriage. But how is it possible Lord?! I have sacrificed my youth to answer to your call! And this is what I get?! I wish I had carried on with my studies, I wish I had traveled with my friends, I wish I had all the experiences a twenty year old has… but I didn’t. Nice swindle Lord! You are just like everyone else! I was blind; I’ve let myself be fooled by the moves of the nuns and the jokes of the friars. What a disappointment, what a failure. Now what? I am alone. After telling my friends, who are far from You, that I was getting married because marriage is a vocation, after telling them that love always comes first, that the Lord can change your life completely, how do I dare asking for help?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank goodness at that time I was far from Assisi and from Rome, and Fr. Giovanni was never answering his phone, otherwise I would have yelled at his face. I was angry, angry with myself, angry with God, and I couldn’t see a way out but admitting the failure of our marriage and the absence of this God the friars talk so much about, the One they call the “Good Father”. Good my a**! What goodness are we talking about! Where is that goodness?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a word saved me: &lt;strong&gt;What if it was grace?!&lt;/strong&gt; A word Fr. Fabio used to say at Mass. Of course just the thought of this made me angry. But then there was a moment when I thought that maybe I wasn’t wrong about God and that this could be &lt;em&gt;my chance to take a leap of faith&lt;/em&gt;. With the last tiny bit of faith I had, almost at my break point, I shouted: “&lt;strong&gt;If You really are what I thought You were, what they told me You are, then I believe you are doing everything right. You are hurting me bad and I don’t see the reason for it, but I trust all this has a meaning and You will show it to me&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I have been through several hard times, but never as hard as this one. I’ve seen way worse things happening to couples like ours, couples who walked in the light of the faith, who had wonderful encounters, who had amazing spiritual fathers and who experienced providence at some time in their marriage. I thought that if I followed His teachings things would go well because He is my Father; He would make things right for me. I was truly deluded and I was praying to some god made of butter and honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not about performing spiritual somersaults; it’s about believing that the one who is mistaken is you and not God. My friend Chiara helped me come to this realization; the most profound truths happen to be the simplest ones. You can be Christian, Buddhist, believe in the zodiac or in Mary Poppins but &lt;em&gt;if your faith doesn’t save you, you are wasting your time&lt;/em&gt;. If you believe in your job or in having fun and those things can’t save you, you’re wasting your time. It’s not about being Christian &lt;strong&gt;so that&lt;/strong&gt; Jesus gives you a job in return, so that Jesus gives you love back. If you are Christian, God guides you outside the domain of your certainties and offers Himself to you, which is much greater than the ideal job, than the perfect love, than the optimal satisfaction. If you say yes to Him, you experience it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what faith is about. Faith is not believing that everything is going to be alright and that jasmine flowers will grow in your garden, just because you went to Assisi and you lived two years of chastity with your girlfriend. Faith is not telling nice happy stories when everything goes well, it ain’t that hard, right?! Faith is not the euphoria and the enthusiasm of singing and dancing with friars and nuns. Faith is trust. &lt;em&gt;Faith is believing that He makes everything good&lt;/em&gt;, even when you feel you are suffering from injustice. Faith is being in the arms of a Father, who loves you so deeply and thoroughly that He wants you to enter your wounds so that He can help you heal them. Faith is seeing beyond - with your eyes closed – as if blind. Faith is not running away from death; it is living death, smelling its stench and regenerating it through Him with a new perfume. Faith is kneeling and trusting when you &lt;em&gt;do not see a meaning, when you do not understand the reason&lt;/em&gt;. Faith is believing that God knows more than you and I. Faith is the humbleness of His servant who does according to His word, even if it goes against the rules for conceiving a child. Faith is realizing that on the other side of the Red Sea there’s a salvation and a joy greater than what you had imagined. Do not stop and cry in front of a sea you deem insurmountable. Don’t give up! Don’t let the Egyptians get to you! Raise that cane and you will see wonders. Climb that mountain to sacrifice what’s dearest to you, the one thing you have been waiting for years and that you finally hold. Go, trust Him! Trust Him with your eyes closed! No one among these men, among our fathers of faith, our brothers, our close friends, has ever been disappointed. None of those who have believed with their eyes closed has been disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God indeed gives us gifts extraordinarily greater than what we ask. We ask for strength and He gives us climbs, we ask for persistence and He gives us a lengthy path, we ask for faith and He gives us the Red Sea. We are children of a God beyond any measure. What a joy! What a blessing! What a Father!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come on my friends, com’on! Let us be loved by Him. Beyond our expectations and beliefs of what is good for our lives, there is a goodness that comes from God that we can’t even imagine, a goodness we can only experience with our eyes closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Com’on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s cross the sea!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alessandra</name></author><summary type="html">You have listened to a beautiful announcement in Assisi. You have been struck and moved by the depth of those words that went straight into the heart. You have seen a truth in them, a truth about your life. You have realized there’s no use in living for those few things you used to fight for, which gave you nothing but burdens in exchange for false certainties. Maybe you were distant and thanks to the announcement in Assisi you have converted and you’ve approached the Church, that mother that everyone judges. You have encountered the Lord. You have believed in a great beauty, in a promise of happiness no one ever made to you.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/with-eyes-closed-faith-beyond-what-you-see.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily prayer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/daily-prayer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily prayer" /><published>2017-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/daily-prayer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/daily-prayer/">&lt;p&gt;Nothing special happens, no particular emotion, but everything simply seems to be &lt;strong&gt;in the right place&lt;/strong&gt;. With my eyes closed, I address my heart and my spirit to God. Full of confidence in Him, I let myself be emptied so as to give space to the Lord, &lt;strong&gt;the One who is&lt;/strong&gt;. It lasts just half an hour: when the alarm goes off again I prepare an orange juice and try to wake up the rest of the crew. And then, like a fixed schedule, the whole day begins: dress up, pack the backpacks, take the children to school and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day can be quite messy and unorganized with three children, a wife, and a house to take care of… but the appointment of the morning prayer remains a stronghold, a secure haven in my day. And in the most turbulent moments, my heart turns there, to His presence. But do not get a wrong impression. I am certainly not a mystic. Nor was I born with this ability. Everything started a little bit more than two years ago, with the wish to carve out some time between me and the Lord beyond just a quick reading of the Gospel or a Mass &lt;strong&gt;on the go&lt;/strong&gt;. I felt the need to know Him better and with no schemes, without having to necessarily speak or recite some prayers. &lt;em&gt;I needed to see Him&lt;/em&gt;, to put myself in His presence, to contemplate in silence. Like when you stop the car to admire a beautiful view or you admire a painting for a few more seconds. &lt;em&gt;So I felt the need to contemplate Him&lt;/em&gt;, the holy might, el todo ponderosa, the Lord of Heaven and Earth, My creator and Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With time this desire became more intense instead of subsiding, making these moments of intimacy with Him impossible to skip. And everything became more meaningful when recently a priest told me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The purpose of your life is to love… and in order to love somebody, you must know him; and in order to know somebody, you must spend time with him. To learn to love God, therefore, you have to spend time together in daily prayer and reading of the Gospel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend time together with God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So not a distracted thought, a last-minute prayer, a request for some worry, but quality time with Him, el todo poderoso!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn to love God &lt;em&gt;you must find this time&lt;/em&gt; to spend with him &lt;em&gt;very day&lt;/em&gt;. Even if your life was the most stressful, every day in the worse traffic jam, or exhausted from a crazy schedule, or assailed from a crew of little ones that call you &lt;strong&gt;mom&lt;/strong&gt; (!) around the clock. &lt;em&gt;You must find the time every day&lt;/em&gt;, so that your life bears fruits with Him and in Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that it should not be anything complicated and it should not even last some interminable hours: 20 minutes a day can be enough! The important thing, however, is &lt;em&gt;to get into a routine&lt;/em&gt;, so that the time in prayer is not an afterthought, the last thing in the day (priority wise), but an integral part of your life, with its physical space and time. Your day should be scheduled with a little bit of monastic order —ora et labora— so that nothing goes lost and you can grab what Jesus calls &lt;em&gt;the best part&lt;/em&gt;. There are various ways to get into this routine and I suggest some ways that have been well-tested by the Church over the centuries… you should be able to find something that can work for you :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-prayer-of-the-hours&quot;&gt;1. The prayer of the hours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever been a guest at a monastery, you know what we’re talking about. The prayer of the hours consists of reading Psalms and other texts inside of a structured formula (contained in the &lt;strong&gt;breviary&lt;/strong&gt;), which marks “the hours” of the day. The most important moments are &lt;strong&gt;Lauds&lt;/strong&gt; of the morning, &lt;strong&gt;Vespers&lt;/strong&gt; in the evening and &lt;strong&gt;Compline&lt;/strong&gt; before going to bed. To begin, try to be faithful to one of these moments, for example before going out in the morning or on the train while going to work. Find a breviary at the bookstore, ask at the parish, or search on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-daily-rosary&quot;&gt;2. The daily Rosary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a prayer loved by many and difficult for just as many others. One thing is certain, the constant and faithful prayer of the Rosary has brought and continues to bring graces upon graces in all of the world! Although praying 50 Hail Marys can seem to be long, in truth it is a prayer that lasts only about 15 minutes. It is our kids’ favorite prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-prayer-of-silence&quot;&gt;3. The prayer of silence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is instead my favorite prayer. It is a prayer of contemplation in the way of the monks. In order to be faithful, it is important to set up a time, place, and duration for the prayer. It begins with the sign of the cross and an invocation to the Holy Spirit. Then you rest and listen to what He wants to say to our heart. As soon as you realize that the mind is wandering in some thought, take a breath and refocus. For example, I say in my heart: Jesus! Then I finish the prayer time with one Hail Mary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-the-reading-of-the-holy-scriptures&quot;&gt;4. The reading of the Holy Scriptures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the friar told me, to know Jesus and to love him you have to know his story. The same friar advised me to &lt;em&gt;read a chapter of the New Testament every day&lt;/em&gt;, starting with the gospel of Matthew until Revelation. Once arrived at the end, start again! This special knowledge of the scriptures puts you in intimacy with Jesus and his word. For me, reading the Gospel in chronological order has been a revelation, making it possible for me to see links throughout Jesus’ life and those of the apostles that I completely didn’t notice before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-the-mass&quot;&gt;5. The Mass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the daily Mass. Receiving the sacrament of the Eucharist every day is a holy blessing (if we are in God’s grace, that is, if we have been to confession). It puts us in Communion with the Church and the brothers and it feeds us the same Jesus whose steps we want to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, these 5 methods are not mutually exclusive - not at all! If it was possible we would have to practice all 5 daily, like they do in monasteries. Just &lt;em&gt;start with one of these&lt;/em&gt;. Learn to be obedient and faithful. You will discover God’s faith and peace in this process. Your eyes will become brighter and your soul, filled with the grace of God through the Holy Spirit, will show you the next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your prayer!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Francesco</name></author><summary type="html">Nothing special happens, no particular emotion, but everything simply seems to be in the right place. With my eyes closed, I address my heart and my spirit to God. Full of confidence in Him, I let myself be emptied so as to give space to the Lord, the One who is. It lasts just half an hour: when the alarm goes off again I prepare an orange juice and try to wake up the rest of the crew. And then, like a fixed schedule, the whole day begins: dress up, pack the backpacks, take the children to school and so forth.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/daily-prayer.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chastity is freedom, not a taboo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chastity-is-freedom-not-a-taboo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chastity is freedom, not a taboo" /><published>2017-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chastity-is-freedom-not-a-taboo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chastity-is-freedom-not-a-taboo/">&lt;p&gt;At that time I was dating a girl and for several months an idea had been whirring in my head. I sensed that the relationship between a man and a woman came about through many means of communication. Imagine the two of you as two lakes connected by several channels, with water passing from one basin to the other: there is the channel of talking, the channel of sharing, the channel of discussing… and there’s the channel of sex. I knew the latter was by far the one with the largest flow rate. And what happens when a communication branch is way larger than the others? All the water goes through that one channel and all the other smaller streams almost run dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-it-mean-in-practice&quot;&gt;What does it mean in practice?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means that in many occasions sex takes the place of other ways of communication, such as talking to each other after a quarrel, being tender, making plans together. Following this intuition, I tried to restrain the sex channel in order to make sure that water went in all directions. The result was a partial failure. But I learned the reason why only later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-love-with-a-person-is-belonging&quot;&gt;Making love with a person is belonging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sex entails our whole being, our body, and our feelings. It is a &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; experience. It is the complete gift of yourself but also it is the full &lt;strong&gt;reception&lt;/strong&gt; of the other. Think carefully whether it is not so! Sex establishes a very strong bond between two people. A beautiful bond. But at the same time, this bond introduces a constraint, a belonging to the other. This explains the pain and the suffering when two lovers break up! When I broke up with a girlfriend I was always left with a sense of &lt;strong&gt;betrayal&lt;/strong&gt; in my heart; a sense that I was betraying the other who had given herself completely to me. And I’m telling this from a merely &lt;strong&gt;human&lt;/strong&gt; point of view. I am certainly not referring to the Genesis here &lt;em&gt;…a man leaves his father and mother and clings to his wife, and the two of them become one body&lt;/em&gt;. My attempt in restraining the sex channel was a failure because the other person felt rejected as if I was denying her the gift of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chastity&quot;&gt;Chastity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the announcement I heard in&lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Assisi&lt;/a&gt; and at the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;10 Commandments course&lt;/a&gt; entailed a great freedom. When two people decide to start dating, they embark on a journey of discovery and discernment for them to commit to each other forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When two people are dating, everything is usually taken too much for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The couple is only &lt;strong&gt;on a trial&lt;/strong&gt;. Hence, everyone has the right to feel absolutely &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; to withdraw from the relationship ‘til the day of the wedding. Chastity is one of the fundamental tools to live this freedom to the fullest. Is it hard and painful? Sure, it can be sometimes, so what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chastity requires courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chastity is unconventional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And where is courage, there are adventure and passion. Someone  who decides to have intercourse is not the real nonconformist! That is the easy way. Chastity instead offers you &lt;strong&gt;a reckless and lively life&lt;/strong&gt;. Try it, and you will see how all the other channels of your relationship will be magnified, as the water of love cleanses and rehabilitates all the streams. You will see how you’ll be able to face each other in freedom, with no undercover or unspoken ties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I want you to ponder one thing. The sexual act is not only a unifying act but also a creative act. Every time you make love with your girlfriend a child can be born. And don’t talk to me about safe sex… I know it well too. The truth is that we can all make mistakes and that condoms do break. This is my personal experience. Maybe you think it is very unlikely, that the probability is one over a hundred or a thousand. Think about this: would you cross the street if they told you that once every hundred times you cross, you are run over and you die?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know several people who believe that sexual intercourse is not a palliative and other people who think it is important to have sex before marriage to be sure you have chosen the right person. Based on my experience I say that it doesn’t actually work this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… and you? Are you still so sure?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Francesco</name></author><summary type="html">At that time I was dating a girl and for several months an idea had been whirring in my head. I sensed that the relationship between a man and a woman came about through many means of communication. Imagine the two of you as two lakes connected by several channels, with water passing from one basin to the other: there is the channel of talking, the channel of sharing, the channel of discussing… and there’s the channel of sex. I knew the latter was by far the one with the largest flow rate. And what happens when a communication branch is way larger than the others? All the water goes through that one channel and all the other smaller streams almost run dry.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/chastity-is-freedom-not-a-taboo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Joy first</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/joy-first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joy first" /><published>2017-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/joy-first</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/joy-first/">&lt;p&gt;Crying, I wondered: how could we manage to take 13 exams in 5 months? At the time when I was a student, five exams already seemed so many… How did we do it? As I was crying and repeating this sentence, I started to think about all the laundries Francesco hung out to give me time to study, the frozen pizzas we had for dinner, our bathroom, inaccessible without spacesuits and oxygen cans, the cabinet drawers, which shall be opened in secret when even our Father who is in heaven doesn’t watch, the moldy cheese in the fridge and the morning miraculous catch of underwear from the mountain range of clothes to fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to talk about us, how good we are or not in reaching the goal, risking to be suffocated by one inch long socks to be coupled and folded. I just want to say that if you’re happy, you can do anything. If you are happy, any goal is at your fingertips; any effort is light. If you are happy there is no effort that can knock you down. &lt;strong&gt;If you chase the most beautiful and important things first, these will give you the joy and determination to do anything else.&lt;/strong&gt; And if the Lord puts His stamp on this joy… then you’ve nailed it; then you savor the fulfillment, the taste of beauty. I think that I would have never been able to spend so many nights on books &lt;strong&gt;if my heart wasn’t resting in the relationship with Francesco&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think if I had not had him, I wouldn’t have known love, I wouldn’t have really known myself, and even the mercy God has for me. Thirteen exams in five months are not a big deal compared to all this. I thank the Lord for His faithfulness to our marriage and for His faithfulness to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, going to University was the opportunity to avoid rushing ahead, and having the possibility to do twenty-year-old things even though I was married and a mom. The Lord has been as faithful with me as He was with Mary: she wanted to consecrate both her body and her soul to Him, &lt;strong&gt;and God made her both virgin and mother&lt;/strong&gt;. The Lord always gives a hundredfold: mother and wife and, shortly, also with a degree (for what it’s worth!). This is a generous God, full of grace and abundant in Love. The last exam is in ten days, and then we uncork some sparkling wine (which is already waiting in the kitchen!).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alessandra</name></author><summary type="html">Crying, I wondered: how could we manage to take 13 exams in 5 months? At the time when I was a student, five exams already seemed so many… How did we do it? As I was crying and repeating this sentence, I started to think about all the laundries Francesco hung out to give me time to study, the frozen pizzas we had for dinner, our bathroom, inaccessible without spacesuits and oxygen cans, the cabinet drawers, which shall be opened in secret when even our Father who is in heaven doesn’t watch, the moldy cheese in the fridge and the morning miraculous catch of underwear from the mountain range of clothes to fold.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/joy-first.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Indeed he was right!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/indeed-he-was-right/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indeed he was right!" /><published>2017-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/indeed-he-was-right</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/indeed-he-was-right/">&lt;p&gt;And then, the other day, I realized that in a warm and rainy autumn of seven years ago, on St Francis’s day, in a chapel in Assisi behind the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Porziuncola Church&lt;/a&gt;, we —really the two of us— exchanged a ring and, with a twenty-year-old voice (I was almost 20, Francesco was 27), we promised eternal faithfulness to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are: we are going through our seventh year!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question was: “So isn’t our marriage supposed to be on the rocks ?”. The second: “How could it happen that SEVEN years have passed and I still don’t have a KitchenAid robot ?”. The third question, however, was more reassuring: “We Raos always rush ahead with everything, probably we got the seven-year itch  in the third year already”. In fact, now that I think of it, on the third year of marriage we were in France since already two years, and our marriage was  definitely in trouble. A very difficult year: with one job about to end  and another one that &lt;strong&gt;wasn’t&lt;/strong&gt; starting, two little girls and so many difficulties. In that third year it seemed that all the other’s flaws came out effortlessly and carelessly, sharp and unbearable. A difficult year indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one thing I remember most of all: I had two paths in front of me, I could give up because “I deserve something better”, or I could give a chance to our marriage and to God, trusting that that famous October 3rd He ensured His presence in our house. I decided to change clothes and equipment to undertake the more adventurous and less clear path and to discover new worlds. We had a furious fight, in which I said that if I had known all his faults  maybe I would have thought twice about marrying him. But he said that the Lord hid them from  me on purpose, because otherwise I would have missed my vocation, which is the most beautiful thing in my life. At this point of the story my most dear Sicilian friend would say - &lt;strong&gt;Miii, raggione c’aveva&lt;/strong&gt;! (Indeed he was right!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he was right indeed, because —having dropped the weapons— I realized that those bad flaws were coincidentally touching the very deepest wounds of my life, and that maybe —and I say maaaaybe— they were  an opportunity to face them. And well, it was really just like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, did our marriage already hit the famous seven-year itch, or the troubles of the third year don’t count? Do we have to renew it? Is it a requirement for a marriage to hit the rocks right on the seventh year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps on the seventh year we should renew our marriage vows before going into troubles. But then this marital crisis… who invited it? Who opened the door to it? And, above all, who wants it? Who does it think it is to dictate law in our house? Maybe it came in while we were too busy paying the increasing electricity bills or organizing the dance classes for the kids, which —go figure why— are always at two different and both uncomfortable times. Or did it visit our place while we were busy on the phone arranging shifts to stay, at least one of us, with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Him: But darling! Don’t you remember?! The two of us together invited it during those boring evenings spent watching TV, when step by step we were no longer planning any dates, we had no projects in which to engage ourselves, each of us began to see his/her own goals, and there was no longer the two of us on our minds, but a whole list of things to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Me: Are you sure? I am usually the one who invites people here, and now that I think of it I wrote Crisis our address by mail, one of  those days when getting through the day with a shower and no vomiting on the shirt was already a success. And I always forgot to smile at you when you were coming back home tired from work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Him: What I remember is that Madame Crisis knocked on the door so many times and I never paid attention, but one day I was tired and I didn’t want to discuss or clarify, so I listened to it right there in front of the door, but I assure you that I didn’t let it in!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Me: So let’s send it away! I will write down everything I must forget no more, and I will thank it because it left us something good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the impression that often we get married with the best intentions, great projects, sometimes facing many difficulties, but then we get lost in trivial daily things to do and we forget how beautiful it is to have a project together, to fully engage in something, to have the time to be alone and rediscover each other, to renew the marriage vows, to &lt;strong&gt;re-marry&lt;/strong&gt;. I think that for us this year is not the seven-year itch one. I have the impression that there is a movement within us and we don’t know where it will lead us, but just talking about it brings us joy and unites us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alessandra</name></author><summary type="html">And then, the other day, I realized that in a warm and rainy autumn of seven years ago, on St Francis’s day, in a chapel in Assisi behind the Porziuncola Church, we —really the two of us— exchanged a ring and, with a twenty-year-old voice (I was almost 20, Francesco was 27), we promised eternal faithfulness to each other.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/indeed-he-was-right.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Aiming for the maximum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/aiming-for-the-maximum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aiming for the maximum" /><published>2017-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/aiming-for-the-maximum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/aiming-for-the-maximum/">&lt;p&gt;Today a dear friend of mine from Spain commented my third awesome pregnant belly reproaching that only the Romanians, “los moros” and Gypsies get to the third child; and then “There are you guys, I just can’t get you”. In fact normal people, those endowed with common sense, realize that today having one child is already a big thing (especially with this crisis), and two are just for the bravest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the first time I hear such a talk; or better: I hear nothing but this. The line of thought makes sense: no job, and so no marriage and no children. Live with a minimal life. It’s the crisis’s fault. Francesco and I have been married for almost seven years, we are very young, we’ve got an insecure employment and a super-permanent job - that is 24 hours a day, weekends included - : mom. We know the crisis very well: last month they announced the shutdown of the center where my husband works. In seven years, we have already lived in three different countries, and we are getting kind of tired of not having a fixed abode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can think of many children who at the age of 10 have the iPhone, brand jeans, the latest model of shoes, play station, etc. A kid is for sure really expensive nowadays! In order to have another child, maybe I should give up smoking, going to the hairdresser monthly, having my nails done at the beautician, getting second car just to drive for 2 or 3 miles, the Wii, and we’ll have to get tighter at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I’ve never heard a kid complaining for non-brand jeans, while I see Chiara’s eyes shining when she plays with her sister, and going crazy with joy in front of mom’s belly. I am more and more convinced that offering our kid a relationship, a sibling indeed, is much better than all the fantastic opportunities we think we can offer him with money. Perhaps a child does not ask for things: he asks for you, he asks you to spend yourself for him. He wants your time, he wants you to watch him while he is doing something, he wants to feel worthy of your gaze. He wants and loves your wrinkles and white hair that even at the age of 27 begin to appear. Our children ask us the patience and - when it’s really used up - they love to see mom giving up and letting them watch the second cartoon of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crisis and its uncertainty are actually teaching me that you have to spend yourself for what is really worth it, without waiting for everything to be perfect. The crisis won’t take away your husband and your kids from you: they are your treasure and the only thing for which it’s worthy spending yourself. Taking control of your life and trusting Someone greater than you - God - isn’t crazy: it’s just another logic, it’s aiming for the maximum.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alessandra</name></author><summary type="html">Today a dear friend of mine from Spain commented my third awesome pregnant belly reproaching that only the Romanians, “los moros” and Gypsies get to the third child; and then “There are you guys, I just can’t get you”. In fact normal people, those endowed with common sense, realize that today having one child is already a big thing (especially with this crisis), and two are just for the bravest.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/aiming-for-the-maximum.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Franciscan March 2002</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/franciscan-march-2002/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Franciscan March 2002" /><published>2016-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/franciscan-march-2002</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/franciscan-march-2002/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Look up in the &lt;a href=&quot;\glossary&quot;&gt;Glossary&lt;/a&gt; to see what the Franciscan March is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesco&lt;/strong&gt; – I’ve got a very clear memory of the night before we started walking. We were seated next to a crumbling wall, surrounded by nature, admiring a magnificent sunset at the end of July. There the friar told us: “Don’t waste this opportunity: walk for something, walk to Assisi asking something to the Lord, something concrete.” Why was I there? I had just started the spiritual journey with Fr. Massimo, and after so much listening I needed to do something practical. Also, I like to put miles under my feet, so the pilgrimage was perfect. After all, if you are not able to soften your heart, the fatigue, the heat and the sore feet will do it for you … so in front of that sunset I asked the Lord to heal my relationships situation. This is why I was walking: in order to be healed from my disastrous love stories, the emotional failures and all those relationships that had never entirely closed (let’s remain friends?) … I was there for this, now I knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alessandra&lt;/strong&gt; - Getting to the March was an endeavor. I was 16 and I was coming from a remote village in Basilicata, where sheep plus inhabitants don’t even get to eight thousand. I definitively wasn’t able to take a train by myself. I went there with my friend Giusy, who was older than me, and – most important - more experienced. The problem was that two days before the departure, Giusy didn’t feel like going anymore, but eventually, for my insistence, we ventured. My first memory of the March is the initial stage: 25 miles! Because of some accident we made two steps in one. Such an unspeakable enterprise for my legs, but especially for my “I am strong, I don’t leave my backpack, I take it, I’m not like the others, I can make it to the end” … and then first I left my backpack, and then humiliated I got on that dying-people-collector truck for the last miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesco&lt;/strong&gt; - The first stop was devastating. Almost 25 miles. Heat, sweat, thirst. We arrived shredded at the destination, in groups of one or two people. At the arrival there were some bowls of fresh water waiting for us to regenerate our destroyed feet. And each one’s arrival was also a surprise for all of us. It’s amazing how sharing arises among people who have gone through the same “suffering.” It happens the same in fatigue sports, such as cycling and athletics. It was the same feeling: we made it, with our legs, with our sweat, with no shortcut, no recommendation. When defensive barriers are so low and masks of the everyday life fell on the street, talking and getting to know people is so easy! Fr. Massimo had “forbidden” me to start a new relationship before I had healed my wounds (and, in particular, before I had closed a situation on which my mind and my heart were still focused). I used to say to myself that I was in a period of “reclaiming”. But for this reason, having no expectations, it was natural to me to go to meet all (all) the girls in the March … On the evening of the first day, there was a small group of girls seated on the ground enjoying the well earned rest. Boldly I went there to know them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your name?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alessandra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(ok stored)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where are you from?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basilicata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(uhmmmm, it’s so far in the south of Italy)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How old are you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sixteen, I just finished the third year of high school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(pffrrr … cof cof)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok let’s move on, I told myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alessandra&lt;/strong&gt; – During the walk, every now and then a guy appeared, a nice guy by the way. One day he said to me: “Hi Alessandra, I was looking for you, I wanted to walk a bit with you!”.  And I – who was in the “Santa Maria Goretti” phase -replied: “Um, ah, well….”, and I thought “Hey what the hell was his name? He calls me by name, maybe we talked before, but I don’t remember, so then who is he?”. But as the days passed, Francesco appeared more and more. The weird thing was that usually nobody used to flirt with my in my hometown, so I had become the “fun” one. But with him it was different: I didn’t have time or energy to be someone, so I was myself, all the way myself. The thing that helped me staying so calm was that it was clear to me that we were too different: Francesco was eight years older than me - which at sixteen years old makes a big difference; he graduated in physics (!!!!) and was doing his PhD (I ignored the meaning and existence of that word) in Zurich, and he was used to speak English with people. I, a random silly girl, was in the third year of high school, I lived in the village next to the one where Carlo Levi was confined, surrounded by goats, and I felt sophisticated when I spoke Italian instead of dialect. I was very surprised by the way Francesco saw things. When I talked with him I felt like I could catch some fresh air of freedom. He said: “You can enroll in a faculty that you think you might like. You commit yourself to it and you take your exams, and then after one year you stop and see if it really is what you want to do. If not, you can change faculty, what’s the problem?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesco&lt;/strong&gt; - The days went by clear and serene. The silence of the morning, the daily rosary and the feet always full of dirt for the journey were giving me great peace. The destination was getting close: the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Porziuncola Church&lt;/a&gt; and the forgiveness of the Father. I don’t know if by chance or will, I spent much time with Alessandra. I enjoyed her simplicity and her purity -“I am the King’s most beautiful daughter”- , they were oxygen for me. They purified me from my boastful life, which was all focused in competing at work and in being the best and the smartest in everything. With Alessandra, instead, it was enough to be myself. It was enough to walk and talk. So, without realizing it, we reached the destination. The friar said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now you can kiss the ground”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we entered the Porziuncola. I shudder as I remember these moments. We entered together, side by side. We were in front of the Father. Many had tears of emotion, tears of joy. We made it, we did our run and we won: we kept faith as St. Paul says. And there the Father’s forgiveness was waiting for us, that forgiveness that He always wants to give, but that we so rarely ask. We were entering into the history, becoming a bit part of those old stones, which were there with St. Francis and his madness of love for Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alessandra&lt;/strong&gt; - After the March I had planned to go to visit my sister in Rome, in order to take a few days of vacation. But when Francesco invited me to go with him I said “Well, I don’t know…”. The embarrassment was up, so I called my sister from a pay phone to tell her that I wouldn’t have gone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mary, look I won’t …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thank goodness you called! I have a problem at work: a girl left, so I absolutely need you to work with me tomorrow, thank goodness!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No, actually I’m calling you because …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You saved me! Thank goodness, I didn’t know what to do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mary, look, I …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the cash ran out, the call disconnected and I couldn’t talk to my sister. Eventually, under a summer downpour, Francesco and I arrived at the Assisi station, and we left to Rome. Three unforgettable days. In the morning I worked with my sister and from lunch onwards Francesco showed me around Rome. We walked a lot. We prayed the rosary in every church we met on the Capitoline, or in St. Paul. It was a really nice, deep and pure friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Francesco&lt;/strong&gt; - After the March, it was time to go back to the ordinary. But how was it possible after living such a moment of grace! Don’t ask me why, but I asked Ale to spend a few days in Rome with me. I wanted to show her my city, not as a tourist but as a Roman. There was no malice, no ulterior motives (for me the difference in age, but above all the different situations we were in: she in high school, me in Switzerland, were insurmountable). She was staying at her sister’s, and I took her around Rome with my bike for three days (true scenes from “Roman Holiday”). Three wonderful days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following months, Alessandra sent me a picture of S. Pietro from the Pincio, taken in those days. I spent so much time looking at that picture again and again. Maybe, in the bottom of my heart, … I had already guessed I had met the &lt;a href=&quot;\is-she-the-woman-of-my-life&quot;&gt;woman of my life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord listened to me. Not only He healed my wounds, but He made sure that Alessandra and I could meet many times in Assisi that year, just for an inexplicable series of God-incidences, which would have led us to start dating one year later.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Francesco</name></author><summary type="html">Look up in the Glossary to see what the Franciscan March is.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/franciscan-march-2002.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Franciscan wedding plan, yes we can!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Franciscan wedding plan, yes we can!" /><published>2016-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can/">&lt;p&gt;I heard this sentence a thousand times: “We can’t get married because we’ve got no money”, where by &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s meant that for the reception. So: first there is the dress, the restaurant, the flowers, the car, the historic church, the photographer, the entertainment, the honeymoon, etc. Then we should please her mum who couldn’t afford much in her days and now wants her daughter’s wedding to be the best one. And don’t forget her family is very large and they are a close family. So, just considering the most intimate ones, they are 150. And what about the little cousins, uncles, aunties, relatives here and relatives there, until the fifth generation on the mom’s side? Well it’s not nice not inviting them, they have been important for me… I absolutely have to find the aunt’s phone number… what was her name??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short: &lt;strong&gt;planning a wedding is a huge stress and, if you think of it this way, it is only affordable to a few Sheikh oil kings.&lt;/strong&gt; But then, let me say, those poor souls that will have to come to this wedding and sit at the tables —which have already been planned by the groom on a night when he was finally free because he fought with his future bride for the color of the wedding announcement— how much will they have to spend for you? In fact at a wedding like this you need to be well dressed, and you can’t wear the dress that you recycled from your sister’s wedding: people can see it in the pictures and it’s embarrassing! And don’t forget the present! Oh gosh, the present! How much are these guys spending for us? At least 60$ per person for a piece of raw lasagna and a dessert that gives stomachache… damn, this means you’re forced to give 100$ each (at least!). Well, there are five of us, what can we do? I can foresee the vacation at the beach house skipping for a wedding, noooo!!! I know it: Chiara will certainly have a fever (even if it’s June), yes: a sudden illness because her grandparents took her to the mountains where there was a bad weather. We can’t give up the beach house for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start over!&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s start all over from the beginning. So, first of all, why are we getting married? Who has to absolutely be there that day? Who are we organizing this party for? &lt;strong&gt;Marriage is primarily a vocation&lt;/strong&gt;, a call to love and joy. It will surely be the best day of our lives, even without a mortgage to set it up (it will be the best day for the &lt;em&gt;promise&lt;/em&gt; it brings, not for the &lt;em&gt;emotions&lt;/em&gt; of the moment). It may have a better start with the rent paid for three months, instead of 15 minutes of fireworks. The main host, if we can call it so, will be the Lord. If He won’t be there everything will simply gets harder and harder. Then, let’s retrace the passages of the Gospel that have marked our history. A week before the big yes, let’s go on a nice retreat, just the two of us, in some hermitage to pray, to fully enter into the mystery of the sacrament we are about to receive. Perhaps during the celebration we can tell the story of providence and beauty that we experienced, so that everyone can be grateful to the Lord and help us to thank Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the organization? The lunch, the music, the dances … the party is for guests, but for sure we are the celebrated ones; so we ourselves need to have fun first. Following the standards perhaps doesn’t always reflect our personalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get into practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-organize-a-beautiful-wedding&quot;&gt;How to organize a beautiful wedding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The announcement:&lt;/strong&gt; we took an A4 sheet and we used the printer at home, which works fine. We divided it into four parts. On the first side there was the invitation to the ceremony and the reception with a clear indication for the gift: “The Lord loves the cheerful giver. As a gift we would like a lot of money. Give what you can —and then Fr. Giovanni Marini forced us to add —and &lt;strong&gt;more than you can&lt;/strong&gt;. This money will be donated to an orphanage in Mozambique”. Below that there was a small map that showed how to reach the church and the reception place, and on the back we gave details about the mission in Mozambique. Alternatively, one can even use the invitations themselves to support those in need. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativelab.5p2p.it/&quot;&gt;we support the projects of Sant’Antonio church in Milan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dress:&lt;/strong&gt; on the Internet you can find really cheap stuff. I was lucky to have a mother who took on the role of dressmaker on the occasion, and so I just spent about 300$ for the fabric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flowers:&lt;/strong&gt; never say they are for a wedding, they’ll fleece you! Five days before the wedding, I went with my sister’s friend to buy 150 gerberas —my favorite flower— and she told the florist they were for a super-Franciscan wedding, meaning that he could not ask for more than 150$, and indeed it was so. At the wedding of a friend of mine, I’ve decorated the church myself: two or three compositions here and there, and a flower on each bench, tied with a ribbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photographer:&lt;/strong&gt; if you rely on a professional, in most cases you will end up with someone who ignores the deep meaning of that day. Lacking the necessary sensitivity, he will pretend to direct the day without really understanding your needs. Here are two solutions: the first is to give the role to a friend who has passion for photography and the necessary equipment. The second option is to call &lt;a href=&quot;http://weddings.5p2p.it&quot;&gt;5loaves2fish&lt;/a&gt; (yes! we also do that). In fact, the posts you are reading, the videos and our witnessing are completely funded by our wedding photography activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; location??? What? 5,000$? What? A parish hall is always easy to find, perhaps with a nice garden (which you’ll really enjoy, if it doesn’t rain —as it happened at our wedding— or you can do it at the country house of a cousin who lives out of town (in France they have this habit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch:&lt;/strong&gt; if the parish hall has a kitchen, you just have to add some scout friend who knows how to get by in any situation, or some volunteer who doesn’t want to give up the beach house to make you a gift; otherwise caterer, nice paper plates, plastic steam glasses and a bit of creativity. My father, for example, brought wine, my grandmother cheese, we bought some cold cuts from a farm, a friend made the cake, the caterer prepared a lasagna and the second course with a side (900€, waiters included, for 80 people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The entertainer:&lt;/strong&gt; a friend who plays the piano bar, a good stereo, etc. Tarantella dance never goes out of fashion…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wedding-mobile:&lt;/strong&gt; as for the car, your cheap car works fine; polished as it was new, with hitched cans hung on the back, it looks cool ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, for our wedding we spent about 2,000$, including the offer for the church and the 10 nights we spent in the adjoining guesthouse. &lt;strong&gt;The most important thing is to put the most important things first&lt;/strong&gt;, and everything else around them. The most important thing is not to be sucked into this chasm of organization, and then look up. At our wedding many guests were in jeans, but we really enjoyed ourselves. The most beautiful gifts were the envelopes full of small change from my college friends, who really gave up a pizza for it and they did it from the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes you can, what do you say?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alescanca</name></author><summary type="html">I heard this sentence a thousand times: “We can’t get married because we’ve got no money”, where by money, it’s meant that for the reception. So: first there is the dress, the restaurant, the flowers, the car, the historic church, the photographer, the entertainment, the honeymoon, etc. Then we should please her mum who couldn’t afford much in her days and now wants her daughter’s wedding to be the best one. And don’t forget her family is very large and they are a close family. So, just considering the most intimate ones, they are 150. And what about the little cousins, uncles, aunties, relatives here and relatives there, until the fifth generation on the mom’s side? Well it’s not nice not inviting them, they have been important for me… I absolutely have to find the aunt’s phone number… what was her name??</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/franciscan-wedding-plan-yes-we-can.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Is he the one?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/is-he-the-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is he the one?" /><published>2016-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/is-he-the-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/is-he-the-one/">&lt;p&gt;And finally, where do I find such a superman willing to pursue me, pursue me? I still have adolescent acne, a butt which is larger than Texas and I have not yet learned how to upload pictures on the computer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some answers for the first two questions, such as these: the perfect man does not exist in reality; or… perhaps I know one, but my friend took him while I was looking for a splinter in his eye. And again, maybe there is, and surely I’ll find him and he will fall at my feet, but no one believes it; actually neither do I. The answer to the third question was clear and firm: “No one would ever choose me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just some thoughts; thoughts of teen Alessandra in her room as she looks at her new pimple in the mirror and says “hell!” In high school I was the friend of the &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; one. So I was the &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; one. &lt;strong&gt;That is, while I was thinking about the coolest guy ever of my life, no one cared about me.&lt;/strong&gt; If someone was flirting with me, he was just embarrassing. Actually I wasn’t much concerned about it because I really felt beautiful inside and my inner life was growing more and more in my deep relationship with God. This used to take a lot of space in my day, both in parish activities and in moments of solitude spent reading the psalms, often surrounded by nature under a big tree on top of a hill. The more space I gave to these things the more I felt fulfilled; so much so that I thought that all I wanted from life was to devote myself to God and to others. Yes, becoming a nun, that was the thing that gave me immense joy. So, after the example of St. Francis and with the enthusiasm of the friars and nuns that I spent time with in Assisi, I put on a pair of sandals, despite the cold of winter and the laughs of my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Father Giovanni, a friar who was my spiritual director, understood where I wanted to end up. And without even talking explicitly about it, he started saying stuff like “&lt;strong&gt;you must learn how to court a man first and then we can try to court God!&lt;/strong&gt;   So you have to court at least 10 guys and then choose the best. No fussing, look among the guys you already know. Go! Don’t forget that the man thinks with the eye: short skirt (very short indeed) heels, makeup, styled hair, etc. Hurry up!”. In fact I hadn’t had any important love story at that time (I was only 17!) So what he said made sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now &lt;strong&gt;where do I find a guy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I find him, he will never want me! I went to the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Porziuncola Church&lt;/a&gt; and thought about whom of the friends in my life I looked up to and who could be worth having a story with. Immediately I thought of my friend Francesco, whom I had met the year before at the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary&quot;&gt;Franciscan March&lt;/a&gt;, but with him it would have never worked. First of all, he belonged to the superman category. Also, he worked in Switzerland and was eight years older than me. Anyway, I took him as a benchmark; he represented the top. Then I made a deal with the Lord: “I am willing to court a man and put on skirts, heels, makeup and everything else only if he is a man (not a kid), that is more or less like my friend Francesco, from him up, I will not settle for less even to go drink a coffee.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, though, a couple of months after that morning at the Porziuncola, Francesco began to call me and to pay attention to me. &lt;a href=&quot;/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life&quot;&gt;He too, was going on his own path&lt;/a&gt;. I began to engage in this relationship, in obedience to Father Giovanni’s suggestions. At first it was just to prove to myself that my life was somewhere else. What scared me most in having a relationship with a guy was that he could take me away from my deep relationship with God. I did not think something so intimate could be shared with anyone else. I fell in love with him head over feet. Not only I was wrong, but that intimacy deeply increased. It was all the more beautiful, more mature, more concrete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion: I met the right man at the Franciscan March, I recognized him as a man I respected in the Porziuncola, and I realized that he was the right one &lt;strong&gt;because he wasn’t perfect, but he could get in the game&lt;/strong&gt;. He made me breathe air of freedom when we were talking about the choices I had to do at the university, and, very importantly, he &lt;a href=&quot;/indeed-he-was-right&quot;&gt;knew how to argue and start again&lt;/a&gt; (which has been very useful) every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; onclick=&quot;location.href='/is-she-the-woman-of-my-life';&quot;&gt;Follow up&lt;/button&gt; on this story by reading Francesco’s version!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alescanca</name></author><summary type="html">And finally, where do I find such a superman willing to pursue me, pursue me? I still have adolescent acne, a butt which is larger than Texas and I have not yet learned how to upload pictures on the computer…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/posts/is-he-the-one.jpg" /></entry></feed>